<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>persistence on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>/tags/persistence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in persistence on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/persistence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS persistence - Spotlight importers and how to create them</title>
      <link>/posts/macos_persistence_spotlight_importers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/macos_persistence_spotlight_importers/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR It works, but very limited due to heavy sandboxing, you can only read and copy files to your sandbox folder or consume some CPU power. If you have a way to escape sandbox then go for it, or could be used as part of a multi-part malware.
Intro I’m reading Jonathan Levin’s *OS Internals Vol I. book (user mode - *OS Internals: - Welcome!), and I got to the chapter where he talks about Spotlight importers, and my first thought was that it would be an awesome way to persist on macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS - Persisting through Application script files</title>
      <link>/posts/macos_persisting_through-application_script_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/macos_persisting_through-application_script_files/</guid>
      <description>I started to explore to possibility of persisting on macOS through script files contained in an application. The basic idea is that if we find a script file, which is being executed by a given application, we can edit that script file, put our code inside, and wait for an execution. Such technique is highly dependent on the applications the user has installed, so I looked through first how rare / frequent is having such scripts inside applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>