<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tcc on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/tcc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tcc on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/tcc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2021-30808 - CVE-2021-1784 strikes back - TCC bypass via mounting</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve-2021-30808/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve-2021-30808/</guid>
      <description>Intro CVE-2021-1784 was a vulnerability that allowed an attacker to bypass TCC by mounting over the ~/Library/Application Support/com.apple.TCC directory and providing a new TCC database. We covered this with Wojciech Regula in or 20+ ways to bypass your mac os privacy mechanisms BlackHat USA talk. This was properly fixed in Big Sur.
The Vulnerability I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but I started to experiment with it again in the very first version of Monterey beta, and found that although the exploit doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, we can mount over the ~/Library directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2020-9771 - mount_apfs TCC bypass and privilege escalation</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve_2020_9771/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve_2020_9771/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR We could mount the entire file system through APFS snapshots as read-only, with the noowners flag, which enables us accessing (almost) every file in the file system, including data (documents, files, etc&amp;hellip;) of every user on the system, including those protected by Apple&amp;rsquo;s privacy framework (TCC). Even with the Guest account we could read files of admin accounts as Guest! 😱
This could be achieved with a single command, for example: mount_apfs -o noowners -s http://com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
