<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/year/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theevilbit.github.io/year/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - 3 - Login Items</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0003/</guid>
      <description>To clear up some expectations. The below tweet is not about this method, that is deferred for now. :)
Login items are probably one of the most well documented methods to persist on macOS. It&amp;rsquo;s widely used by various application to launch themselves upon user login. These applications show up in the menubar most of the time.
There are two ways of setting up Login Items.
Launch Services Framework The first method is using the Launch Services Framework, to which the API reference can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - 2 - iTerm2 startup command</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0002/</guid>
      <description>If the first part was about Terminal and shell profiles, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to mention iTerm2, which is a popular Terminal alternative on macOS. It&amp;rsquo;s being used by many people, especially power users.
When we start iTerm2 it starts the same shell environment as Terminal, and thus the same startup files apply here as well. However this application has an additional way to execute code.
In the Profile settings, there is an option, which is Send text at start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - 1 - shell startup files</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0001/</guid>
      <description>Shell startup files are executed when our shell environment like zsh or bash is starting up. macOS defaults to /bin/zsh these days, and whenever we open Terminal or SSH into the device, this is the shell environment we are placed into. bash and sh are still available, however they have to be specifically started.
When we start zsh it checks number of files, and if there is an environment variable or command inside, it will be set or executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_intro/</guid>
      <description>I was always amazed by @Hexacorn&amp;rsquo;s Beyond good ol&#39; Run key blog post series, which collects various persistence methods on Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s an awesome series, which has 133 parts at the time of this writing. I find them pretty cool, and if you are doing either offensive or defensive work on Windows, this is a must read and follow blog.
In the past years as my interest in macOS grew, and now that I&amp;rsquo;m mostly doing only macOS related research and studies I started to came across many - many tricks, which allows someone to do persistence on macOS beyond just the LaunchDaemons or LaunchAgents directories, which is used to store the launchd startup files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About com.apple.private.security.clear-library-validation</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/com.apple.private.security.clear-library-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/com.apple.private.security.clear-library-validation/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR On macOS 10.15.2 Apple introduced the com.apple.private.security.clear-library-validation entitlement, which is slowly replacing the previously used com.apple.security.cs.disable-library-validation entitlement on system binaries. Although their impact is the about the same, the way they work is different. While library validation is automatically disabled using com.apple.security.cs.disable-library-validation, with com.apple.private.security.clear-library-validation, the application has to disable it for itself through a csops system call.
Intro With the release of Big Sur, I noticed that many of the system binaries have a new entitlement, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t see before, and that is com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divide and Conquer - A technique to bypass NextGen AV</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/divide_and_conquer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/divide_and_conquer/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR This blog post describes a generic technique I called internally on our red team assessment &amp;ldquo;Divide and Conquer&amp;rdquo;, which can be used to bypass behavioral based NextGen AV detection. It works by splitting malicious actions and API calls into distinct processes.
Intro Back in 2019 I was part of a red team, where our daily activity was to bypass a specific NextGen AV. I had this idea I called &amp;ldquo;divide and conquer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
