<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/year/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theevilbit.github.io/year/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - 31 - BSM audit framework</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0031/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0031/</guid>
      <description>This is part 31 in the series of &amp;ldquo;Beyond the good ol&amp;rsquo; LaunchAgents&amp;rdquo;, where I try to collect various persistence techniques for macOS. For more background check the introduction.
macOS implements the OpenBSM audit framework created by McAfee, which allows someone to audit system events, like login, file access, etc… This has been part of the system for very long time. Auditing has several components, the main one being the kernel, which handles all the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the good ol&#39; LaunchAgents - 30 - The man config file - man.conf</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0030/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/beyond/beyond_0030/</guid>
      <description>This is part 30 in the series of &amp;ldquo;Beyond the good ol&amp;rsquo; LaunchAgents&amp;rdquo;, where I try to collect various persistence techniques for macOS. For more background check the introduction.
I was watching an old BSidesLuxemburg 2019 talk by Aaron Jewitt, called &amp;ldquo;Threat Hunting On Linux And Mac With Auditbeat System Module&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s up on YouTube. Aaron mentioned in one of the slides that you can persist using man.conf files. It looked really odd, I tried to quickly Google it, but haven’t found anything about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2022-22655 - TCC - Location Services Bypass</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve-2022-22655/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/cve-2022-22655/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick blogpost about a vulnerability I covered in our Black Hat Europe 2022 talk with Wojciech Regula.
In contrary to what people would expect, clients which can access location services are not maintained in one of the TCC databased, but in a separate location, and it&amp;rsquo;s maintained by locationd. This has been also recently covered by Howard Oakley, in his Privacy: what TCC does and doesn’t blogpost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
