<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS - Getting root with benign AppStore apps</title>
      <link>/posts/getting_root_with_benign_appstore_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting_root_with_benign_appstore_apps/</guid>
      <description>This writeup is intended to be a bit of storytelling. I would like to show how I went down the rabbit hole in a quick ’research’ I wanted to do, and eventually found a local privilege escalation vulnerability in macOS. I also want to show, tell about all the obstacles and failures I run into, stuff that people don’t talk about usually, but I feel it’s part of the process all of us go through, when we try to create something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 ubridge SETUID bit - arbitrary file read</title>
      <link>/posts/gns3_ubridge_setuid_bit_arbitrary_file_read/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gns3_ubridge_setuid_bit_arbitrary_file_read/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I had the idea of scanning my Mac for files that has the SUID bit set, I wanted to see if there is anything interesting showing up. You can do it this way:
/usr/bin/sudo find / -perm -4000 -exec /bin/ls -ldb {} \; &amp;gt; suidfilelist There was one item that caught my attention, and that was a file called ubridge inside GNS3. I used to be a network guy, and GNS3 is a great tool to emulate real network gear, practice configuration, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS - Persisting through Application script files</title>
      <link>/posts/macos_persisting_through-application_script_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/macos_persisting_through-application_script_files/</guid>
      <description>I started to explore to possibility of persisting on macOS through script files contained in an application. The basic idea is that if we find a script file, which is being executed by a given application, we can edit that script file, put our code inside, and wait for an execution. Such technique is highly dependent on the applications the user has installed, so I looked through first how rare / frequent is having such scripts inside applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Fusion 11 - Guest VM RCE - CVE-2019-5514</title>
      <link>/posts/vmware_fusion_11_guest_vm_rce_cve-2019-5514/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vmware_fusion_11_guest_vm_rce_cve-2019-5514/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR You can run an arbitrary command on a VMware Fusion guest VM through a website without any priory knowledge. Basically VMware Fusion is starting up a websocket listening only on the localhost. You can fully control all the VMs (also create/delete snapshots, whatever you want) through this websocket interface, including launching apps. You need to have VMware Tools installed on the guest for launching apps, but honestly who doesn’t have it installed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>