<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xpc on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/xpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xpc on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/xpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure coding XPC Services - Part 5 - PID reuse attacks (CVE-2020-14977)</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part5/</guid>
      <description>In the last post of the series we will see another typical issue, where XPC services using the connecting process&amp;rsquo;s ID (PID) to verify the client instead of the audit token. We will use F-Secure SAFE again for our case study, the vulnerability was fixed in 17.8 and it was assigned CVE-2020-14977.
The root cause The XPC services of F-Secure SAFE use the process ID (PID) to verify the client&amp;rsquo;s signature, as can be seen in the code below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure coding XPC Services - Part 4 - Improved client authorization (CVE-2020-14978)</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part4/</guid>
      <description>F-Secure SAFE XPC service exploitation (CVE-2020-14978) Intro In this post we will look into an other case study which will show us (again) why XPC client verification is crucial in XPC security, and how added authorization checks can slightly improve (but not fix) the problem. The F-Secure SAFE XPC services installed on macOS were not sufficiently hardened, and a malicious actor had the ability to interact with them. The vulnerability was fixed in version 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure coding XPC Services - Part 3 - Incorrect client verification (CVE-2020-0984)</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part3/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft AutoUpdate macOS privilege escalation vulnerability (CVE-2020-0984) Introduction This is the third post in my series which is trying to help Apple developers to avoid typical insecure coding practices. This one will highlight why XPC client hardening and proper verification is extremely important when we use XPC messaging on macOS between clients that run as a normal user and services that run as root. If this validation is not right, it opens up the possibility for an attacker to run privileged commands or worse case, achieve full privilege escalation on the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure coding XPC Services - Part 2 - Checking CS (CodeSigning) flags of the client</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting for some bug fixes to release the previously planned posts, and in the meantime I continue to poke at other PrivilegedHelperTools. This post born because I actually failed to exploit an XPC service, and I learned something new in regards, of how to securely write such a service. One application that came to my sight is Viscosity. This tool was already in Tyler Bohan&amp;rsquo;s list, where his team looked on exploiting such services: GitHub - blankwall/Offensive-Con: Talk and materials for Offensive Con presentation - Privileged Helper Tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure coding XPC services - Part 1 - Why EvenBetterAuthorization is not enough? (CVE-2019-20057)</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/secure_coding_xpc_part1/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part of a blog post series I plan about PrivilegedHelperTools that exists on macOS systems. I recently took a look on a couple of these tools, and found that it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make the code insecure, as there are many small pieces to it, and if one is done wrong, the helper tool will be open to abuse by anyone having a foothold on the system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
