<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gatekeeper on theevilbit blog</title>
    <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/gatekeeper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gatekeeper on theevilbit blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://theevilbit.github.io/tags/gatekeeper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GateKeeper - Bypass or not bypass?</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/gatekeeper_bypass_or_not_bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/gatekeeper_bypass_or_not_bypass/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR On macOS Mojave Gatekeeper only verifies executables, which are run with the open command or the user double clicks. It won’t verify files, that are executed through other means like, directly executing a binary ./myapp regardless of the quarantine attribute. If you can place a plist file inside LaunchAgents/LaunchDaemons, the command inside will also be executed. Prior to Catalina there is a way to trick users to drag &amp;amp; drop files in the LaunchAgents folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few click RCE via GitHub Desktop macOS client with Gatekeeper bypass and custom URL handlers</title>
      <link>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/few_click_rce_via_github_desktop_macos_client_with_gatekeeper_bypass_and_custom_url_handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theevilbit.github.io/posts/few_click_rce_via_github_desktop_macos_client_with_gatekeeper_bypass_and_custom_url_handlers/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR The GitHub Desktop app doesn’t add the quarantine extended attribute to files downloaded from the web, and this along with macOS’s URL handler auto-registration feature allows an attacker to execute arbitrary, even unsigned code on a macOS system. If we don’t count the clicks required to open the GitHub App, and cloning an external repository, then this is a 2 click RCE.
The idea I recently came across a very good blog post about an RCE vulnerability on GitHub Desktop: GitHub Desktop RCE (OSX) - André Baptista via its custom URL handlers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>